Guide to the Eugene O'Neill, Jr. Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1862-1947; Series IV; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  - FAMILY
    - O'Neill, Eugene, Jr.
      - Swimming nude with [Anna Barr?] (2 versions), [194-] (Box 7, Folder 245)
    - O'Neill, Sally
      - Standing next to horse, [1939] (Box 7, Folder 246)
      - Riding horse, [1939] (Box 7, Folder 246)
      - Sitting in doorway holding cat, [1939] (Box 7, Folder 246)
      - Standing on bridge, [1939] (Box 7, Folder 247)
      - Sitting on lawn chair at Pardee Morris House (New Haven, Conn.), [194-?] (Box 7, Folder 248)
      - Sitting on lawn chair next to Marjorie F. Hayward at Pardee Morris House (New Haven, Conn.), [194-?] (Box 7, Folder 248)
      - Cutting wood in background; dog in foreground, [194-?] (Box 7, Folder 249)
    - [Pitt-Smith, George, Jr.?]
      - Portrait, [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 250)
      - Playing banjo in driveway, [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 251)
      - Standing holding cat outside house, [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 252)
    - Pitt-Smith, Kathleen
      - Portraits (4), [1889-91] (Box 7, Folder 253)
      - Portraits (4), [1891-95] (Box 7, Folder 254)
      - Portraits (3), [1898-1901] (Box 7, Folder 255)
      - Portraits (6), [1903-191-?] (Box 7, Folder 256)
      - Sitting on boathouse ramp with unidentified woman, [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 257)
      - Portrait, [194-?] (Box 7, Folder 258)
  - OTHER PEOPLE
    - Bry, Lois Williams
      - Portrait, [193-?] (Box 7, Folder 259)
        Inscribed by Bry to EO, Jr.
      - Sitting next to Cabot on ranch, [194-] (Box 7, Folder 260)
      - Wearing cowboy hat, smoking, [194-] (Box 7, Folder 261)
    - Bry, N. William. Wearing cowboy hat, standing in front of tree, [194-] (Box 7, Folder 262)
    - Bry, Tommy. Sitting on sled, 1937 Mar 22 (Box 7, Folder 263)
    - The Coleman Brothers. Portrait of six musicians, signed by each, [194-?] (Box 7, Folder 264)
    - Lander, Ruth Reade. Portrait by James Viles, Inc., [194-?] (Box 7, Folder 265)
    - Unidentified
      - Woman leaning against table, [18--?] (Box 7, Folder 266)
        Possibly grandmother of Kathleen Pitt-Smith.
      - Students at military academy (3 versions) (copy prints), [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 267)
      - Man and woman sitting outside on bench, [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 268)
      - Woman wearing bathing suit on boat (4 versions), [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 269)
      - Woman sitting next to man on boat (copy print), [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 269)
      - Woman sleeping on boat (copy print), [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 269)
      - People sitting near boat on beach (2 versions), [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 270)
      - People wearing bathing suits on beach (3 versions), [193-?] (Box 7, Folder 271)
      - Man with dog in field (2 versions) (copy prints), [193-?] (Box 7, Folder 272)
      - Man with German shepherd dog in field (copy print), [193-?] (Box 7, Folder 272)
      - Baby crying, [194-?] (Box 7, Folder 273)
  - PLACES
    - Amsterdam (Netherlands). Boats (4 versions) (1 copy print), [1932] (Box 8, Folder 274)
    - Lois Williams Bry's ranch (Ennis, Mont.). Four views, [1939] (Box 8, Folder 275)
    - Ennis (Mont.). Two postcards of Main Street, [193-?] (Box 8, Folder 276)
    - [Europe?]. Twelve scenes (copy prints), [193-?] (Box 8, Folder 277)
    - Germany. Nineteen shots of scenes and people (copy prints), [1932-33] (Box 8, Folder 278)
    - Iceland. Packet of thirteen tourism pictures, [1933?] (Box 8, Folder 279)
    - "Iceland, Sea-Voyage, England, Norway," views, [1933?] (Box 8, Folder 280)
      With envelope in EO, Jr.'s hand.
    - Northport (N.Y.). Boat trip (12 shots of scenes and people), [193-?] (Box 8, Folder 281)
    - Pardee Morris House (New Haven, Conn.). Nine views, [194-] (Box 8, Folder 282)
    - Unidentified
      - Living room with fireplace, [191-?] (Box 8, Folder 283)
      - Bicycles and carriages on porch, [191-?] (Box 8, Folder 284)
      - Houses near park (2 versions) (copy prints), [193-?] (Box 8, Folder 285)
      - Four winter scenes, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 286)
      - Trees near water (copy print), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 287)
  - ALBUMS
    - "Snap Shots", [1920s-1930s]
      For list of contents, see: Appendix
    - Trip to Europe
      - Album #1, [1932-33]
        Includes scenic photographs and ephemera regarding Amsterdam (Netherlands); and in Germany: Freiburg im Breisgau; Breisach am Rein; Munich; Ulm; and Staufen im Breisgau.
      - Album #2, [1932-33]
        Includes scenic photographs and ephemera regarding Freiburg im Breisgau (Germany); Munich (Germany); and Iceland. Also includes photographs of Casa Genotta (Sea Island, Ga.): Balconies, [1932 Oct]; Goldfish pond, [1932 Oct]; From beach, [1933 May]; Goldfish pond, [193-]; Windows of Eugene O'Neill's study, [193-].
    - "Candid Shots", [1937-40]
  - OTHER
    - Cat looking out of window (Box 8, Folder 288)
    - Cats. Six shots (copy prints), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 289)
    - Cats, with envelope labeled "Diomedes, [Stuenelis?], Peggy, Topaz, etc., Mopsus, Zachemiah." Thirty-four shots (copy prints), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 290-291)
      Unidentified woman in some photographs.
    - Cats, with envelope labeled "Pythagoras [and] Brun hilde." Forty-one shots (copy prints) (Box 8, Folder 292-294)
    - Photograph of drawing of boats (copy print), n.d. (Box 8, Folder 295)
    - Pumas, leopards, and lions at German zoo. Seven shots (copy prints), [1932-33] (Box 8, Folder 296)
    - Soldiers Memorial Foote Fellowship. Certificate of award (copy print), 1932 Mar 14 (Box 8, Folder 297)
- 2001 Addition, 1928-1949; Series V; 0.62; 2 boxes
  Arrangement
  Series V, 2001 Addition, is organized into two subseries: Correspondence and Other Papers. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically.
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Bry, Lois Williams, 1928-49, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 336-346)
    - Carrithers, David, 1938 Jan 4 (Box 16, Folder 347)
    - Linforth, Ivan M. (Ivan Mortimer), 1942 Oct 12 (Box 16, Folder 348)
    - Porzig, Walter, 1930 Sep 18 (Box 16, Folder 349)
    - Others, 1948 May 25 (Box 16, Folder 350)
  - OTHER PAPERS
    - Cards, 1946, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 351)
    - Clippings, 1946, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 352)
    - Handkerchief (Box 16, Folder 353)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 354)
    - Postcards, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 355)
    - Untitled draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 356)
    - Wedding announcement, 1939 Jul 3 (Box 16, Folder 357)
- Oversize, 4.6; (5 boxes) + 3 broadside folders
  - "Candid Shots" (in Series IV), [1939] (Box 9, Folder 298)
  - "Snap Shots" (in Series IV), [192-?-193-] (Box 10, Folder 299)
  - Trip to Europe
    - Album #1 (in Series IV), [1932-33] (Box 11, Folder 300)
    - Album #2 (in Series IV), [1932-33] (Box 12, Folder 301)
  - Scrapbook of clippings and photographs regarding Eugene O'Neill, Jr. (in Series III), 1945-46 (Box 13, Folder 302)
  - O'Neill, Eugene, Jr. "S. V. Benét's John Brown's Body ," proof, corrected (in Series II), [1949] (Box Bsd, folder 303)
  - O'Neill, Eugene, Jr. Grades for undergraduate study at Yale (in Series III) (Box Bsd, folder 304)
  - Young Men's Christian Associations. International Committee. Certificate for Honorable Mention in Radio Script Contest for "Choice for North America" (in Series III) (Box Bsd, folder 305)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.2; (1 box)
  Box 14, Restricted Fragile, contain fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order and may only be seen with the permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies or photographic prints have been substituted in the main files for reference use.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 10 (Box 14, Folder 306)
  - Box 1, folder 15 (Box 14, Folder 307)
  - Box 1, folders 26, 29-30, 33 (Box 14, Folder 308)
  - Box 1, folder 36 (Box 14, Folder 309)
  - Box 2, folder 43 (Box 14, Folder 310)
  - Box 2, folder 48 (Box 14, Folder 311)
  - Box 2, folder 66 (Box 14, Folder 312)
  - Box 2, folder 71 (Box 14, Folder 313)
  - Box 2, folder 73 (Box 14, Folder 314)
  - Box 2, folder 74 (Box 14, Folder 315)
  - Box 2, folders 76-77 (Box 14, Folder 316)
  - Box 2, folder 78 (Box 14, Folder 317)
  - Box 2, folder 80 (Box 14, Folder 318)
  - Box 3, folder 92 (Box 14, Folder 319)
  - Box 3, folder 93 (Box 14, Folder 320)
  - Box 3, folder 106 (Box 14, Folder 321)
  - Box 4, folder 139 (Box 14, Folder 322)
  - Box 4, folders 151-152 (Box 14, Folder 323)
  - Box 5, folder 153 (Box 14, Folder 324)
  - Box 5, folder 156 (Box 14, Folder 325)
  - Box 5, folder 158 (Box 14, Folder 326)
  - Box 5, folder 161 (Box 14, Folder 327)
  - Box 5, folder 170 (Box 14, Folder 328)
  - Box 6, folder 194 (Box 14, Folder 329)
  - Box 6, folder 195 (Box 14, Folder 330)
  - Box 6, folder 196 (Box 14, Folder 331)
  - Box 6, folder 200 (Box 14, Folder 332)
  - Box 7, folder 221 (Box 14, Folder 333)
  - Box 7, folder 236 (Box 14, Folder 334)
  - Box 7, folder 241 (Box 14, Folder 335)